Register of the Nikander I. Miroliubov Papers, 1918-1927
Hoover Institution Archives
Nikander I. Miroliubov Papers,
1918-1927
36007
Miroliubov, Nikander Ivanovich, 1870-1927
2 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope. (0.9 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and clippings, relating to the investigation of the deaths of the Romanovs, 1918-1920, the creation of the first Far Eastern Republic, and Russian émigré organizations in the Far East, 1921-1927.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Nicholas II, emperor of Russia, 1868-1918.; Romanov, House of.; Russians--East Asia.; Dal'nevostochnaia Respublika.; East Asia.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation).; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1919-1926
  Correspondence, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Antony, Metropolitan, 1921 (Box 1.)
  - Berdnikov, S. I., 1919
  - Burlin, P., 1925-26
  - Iordanskii, V., 1919
  - Khorvat, Dimitrii L., 1924, 1926
  - Kropotkin, Aleksei Alekseevich, 1920-22
  - Lokhvitskii, General, 1922
  - Sokolov, N. I., 1919-1922 (originals in Safe #5)
  - Miscellaneous
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1926
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, lists, notes, printed matters, etc., arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Bolshevik crimes and offences in Os' and Osinskii Region, 1919 (Box 1.)
  - "General and Economic Situation in Vladivostok and Nikolk-Uss. at the End of April 1923" (in Russian)
  - Harbin Diocese (Russian Orthodox Church)
  - Lenin's letter to an old friend, June 10, 1921
  - Monarchist Union
  - Obituaries
  - Priamur Provisional Government
  - Priamur Zemsky Sobor
    - General, 1922-23
    - Correspondence, 1922-23
  - Russian Non-Socialist Organizations in Harbin, China
    - General
    - Incoming correspondence, 1921 (Box 2.)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1921
  - Testimony concerning events relating to the Imperial Family in Ekaterinburg, February 26, 1920
  - "To the Russian Intelligentsiia," (in Russian) by S. Kolokolnikov
- MISCELLANY (Box 2)
  Miscellaneous notes, clippings, typescripts, etc.